嘿嘿，这里是STH的Patrick
hey guys this is patrick from sth and
今天我们来看看超微SYS-220GQ-TNAR+
today we're going to take a look at the super micro SYS-220GQ-TNAR+
这台服务器可不一般
now this system is actually really cool
它是一台NVidia“红石”
because it is a nvidia redstone platform
这个代号意味着这是一台有4个NVidia A100 GPU的服务器
and what that practically means is that we get to take a look at a system that has four nvidia a100 gpus these gpus can
并且这些GPU能以更高的TDP运行，因为这些GPU是SXM4接口的
actually run at higher tdp and higher power because they are in an sxm4 form
同时这些GPU还使用NVLink进行互联
factor but they also get NVLink between all the different gpus which is a
NVLink是一种高速互联技术
high-speed interconnect so you can have
能让GPU与GPU之间实现高速通讯
gpu to gpu communication and it all is really fast
我们在STH上已经做过了好几个红石服务器的评测了
now we definitely have done reviews of a number of these redstone systems on sth already but this one was
但这台有所不同
different and the reason i wanted to look at this one is because it is not
我之所以想看看这台服务器，是因为它不是基于AMD EPIC平台的
based on the amd epic platform instead
而是基于Intel第三代至强可拓展处理器，代号IceLake
it's based on the third generation intel xeon scalable codenamed icelake and that
这一点使得它尤为不同，因为一些你懂的原因
makes it a little bit different than some of the other options in the industry and just first just so you know
Intel和AMD在某些项目上是互有胜负的
for some workloads it is a little better to have amd and other workloads intel's
超微选择把两家平台都做了，但不论如何我还是比较想看看Intel版本的服务器
a little better so it is kind of cool that super micro has both but i really wanted to go look at the intel version specifically
以后会有一系列相关的视频，因为我们获得了进入超微演示厅的批准
now we're doing this as part of a series where we got the keys to the super micro demo room they said
所以还等什么呢？让我们赶紧过去吧
just go for it and so what i want to do is why don't we get over to super micro and go take a look at this box
[Music]
在正式开始这个视频之前我想强调一下
before we get too far in this video i do want to note something that is super important
我们把这个视频标记为了“被赞助的”（译者注：钱是个STH的，不是给我的，我不需要打星标）
sponsored and the reason for that is we are marking this video as
那是因为我现在我住的地方不像之前一样，离超微只有15分钟路程
that i don't necessarily live 15 minutes away from supermicro anymore instead i
我现在住在德克萨斯州奥斯汀
live in austin texas and so both i flew
所以我和Joe都得坐飞机去超微那边
out joe flew out and so supermarket was
所以超微就帮我们报销了差旅费
helping us cover the you know flight costs and travel costs and stuff like that to be able to go and actually do
但他们只是给了我们进入演示厅，以及测试里面服务器的权利
this but they basically just gave me the keys to the demo room and so they also gave us keys to the demo room and let us
他们没有干预我们的创作内容
use these boxes but they basically said hey you know go do your thing go do whatever you want to go do and they did
他们没有给我们塞钱，这期视频的内容完全是独立编辑的
not give me a script this is all being done completely editorially independent
和我们在STH上做的评测性质是一样的
just like everything we do on sth so i
以上只是为了让各位了解为什么这个视频被标记为“被赞助的”
just want to be very clear that that's what's going on and that's why we're marking this as sponsored with that
接下来让我们到超微那边去吧
supermicro let's get over to
好的，我的计划是从前往后看整台服务器
and so the basic plan is we're gonna start at the front of the system and we're gonna move our way to the rear of the system and
在此之间，我们再具体介绍这台服务器的不同部分，以及这台服务器特殊的点
we're gonna just talk about all the different parts and what makes this system tick
先让我们从服务器的前面开始吧
so let's get to it and let's start with the front of the chassis on
前面板有4个SSD或者说2.5英寸硬盘位
the front of the system we get a total of four ssd or hard drive they're two and a half inch bays most likely you're going to
这几个硬盘位只是SATA接口的，因为它们只是用来安装启动盘的
use these as probably sata bays just because of well they're probably like
more like a boot ssd
一般来说这类服务器不会有太多的存储空间
typically these servers do not have that much storage
因为这类服务器的目标是尽可能地重视GPU，以及让它们能获取到充足的电力
because the goal is really to have as much power and as much focus as you can on the gpus and so that's why that's
接下来我们来看看一个细节，那就是这台服务器只有4个风扇
like that now this might seem like a small detail but there are actually a total of four fans on the system and
这几个风扇单元强的离谱
they are absolutely crazy fan units
因为这四个风扇要冷却四个GPU、高功耗CPU以及后面的网络设备
because these four fan units have to cool this entire system including these four gpus hot cpus and all of the networking that's in the back and one of
这些风扇还有一个很酷的功能  ，看看风扇单元上的这些通风板条
the cool features of these fans is actually that there are these little vent slats that go in these fan units
这个设计和我们之前见过的很多超微服务器都不一样
and so like this is something that's different than a lot of the super micro systems that we've seen to date and it's
拆解机器的时候属实惊艳到我了
just kind of a cool little thing i saw while tearing apart the system
好的，把视角挪到风扇以及硬盘笼之后，来到整台服务器的主要区域
okay now behind the fans and the hard drive or ssd base what we also get is the main
这应该是整台服务器最有特色的地方了
part of the system or probably the biggest feature of the system and that
这是NVidia红石平台的基础部分
is this is a nvidia redstone based system
众所周知，NVidia的低端GPU是以PCI-E形式出售的
now if you don't know how nvidia gpus are sold at the kind of lower end
和以往的PCI-E GPU是一样的
what you get is the pcie gpus that we've seen for years above the pcie gpus you
在那些PCI-E GPU之上，就是我们眼前的整台NVidia红石平台
get the nvidia redstone platform and that's exactly what this is this has
其中包括四块GPU，同时可以给GPU提供额外的电力以及散热能力
four gpus and you get additional power and cooling delivery to these gpus and
能让你在每个GPU上榨取更多的性能
that basically allows you to have more performance per gpu which makes you
让你在这些昂贵的GPU上花的钱更值
basically better able to utilize your investment in these expensive gpus
这个锁扣机构也让我印象很深
something that i think is super cool on this is that there's actually a big giant latching mechanism that latches
把整个红石平台的基板锁定在服务器上
this nvidia redstone board to the super micro system over here and i just think
我没别的意思，只是觉得这个东西超级帅
this is super cool to look at and i've probably done it a couple times on the
我今天把玩过好几次了，很好玩
system already today and i really like this
除此之外，你还能看到这些给GPU供电的电缆，非常粗壮
the other thing that you're going to see is that we have these giant power cables and those are really kind of feeding all the power to these gpus
因为不管你买的是40G还是80G版本的A100 GPU，每个GPU都要消耗超过400W的电力，这会是一个大挑战
because you can have at least 400 watts per gpu you can have either 40 gig or 80 gig versions of the a100 gpus so this is definitely a big solution
这台服务器在HPC领域非常畅销
it's also very popular in the high performance computing industry and markets because
相比于更高端的8 GPU机型，你不需要使用
NVSwitch you basically don't have the nv switches that you have on the kind of eight gpu and higher systems and so it's just kind
因为它的拓扑更简单，耗电量更少，因此很多人都更喜欢它
of an easier topology it's a lower power topology and it's one that a lot of people like because of that
在GPU之后，就到了处理器部分，这里用到了第三代可拓展至强处理器，代号IceLake
now behind the gpus we get these processors now these are third generation intel xeon scalable processors codenamed ice lake
相比于上一代28核心提高了，这代我们可以最高上到40核心
and that means we get up to 40 cores in this generation up from a total of 28 cores in the previous generation we also
此外得到了内存通道数量上的升级，从上一代的6通道内存
get more memory channels we go from six channel memory in the second generation
升级到了现在的8通道内存，另外还可以用DDR4 3200内存
up to eight channel memory in this new third generation and that means that we also get to use ddr4 3200 and so overall
总的来说，现在我们能使用更多的内存带宽，来喂饱CPU和GPU
we get more memory bandwidth to feed the high speed processors as well as the gpus something else that you could
这台服务器还能使用Intel DCPMM 200系列
potentially do with the system is you could also have intel optane dc persistent memory 200 or pmem200 in the
通过内存接口提供高带宽的持久内存
system which gives you persistent memory that you can have a very high bandwidth you know memory interface too and so
我们已经做了很多关于Intel DCPMM的内容了，此外还有一条有关它的视频
that's something you can totally look at we've done a lot with the intel optane dc persistent memory we actually have an entire piece on that that we'll link
我们会把链接放在不存在的简介中，你可以去看看
in the description if you want to go check that out and learn a little bit more about it
IceLake 处理器还有一个关键特性，那就是PCI-E Gen4
but the other key feature that we have in these IceLake processors is we also get pci gen4 which means we
能让CPU和GPU之间拥有更高的带宽
have a faster and higher bandwidth interface between the cpus and the gpus
更快的接口能让数据传输得更快，以此获得更多的性能
that faster interface means that you can transfer data between the two faster and that gives you more performance just from that
这代CPU有更多的PCI-E通道
but since these cpus in this generation get more pcie lanes we actually get 128 pcie lanes in these two
这两颗处理器使我们获得了128条PCI-E，但4颗GPU只需要64条PCI-E通道
processors but we only have four gpus that only use 64 pcie lanes and what
这就意味着我们能给其他设备提供更多通道，比如说网卡，以及其他加速器
that practically means is that there's more lanes available for other devices such as networking cards or other accelerators and that
因此我们来看看服务器的后面
really gets us to the rear of this system now on the rear of the system
我们简单介绍一下后面的PCI-E拓展插槽
we'll talk about those expansion slots those pcie lanes uh just really briefly
这些插槽都是半高的，可以基于需要配置为不同的形式
you have a number of pcie slots these are low profile slots that can be configured in different ways in the system depending on you know what kind of devices that you need
理论上支持最高6个设备
but you could in theory have up to i guess six devices in the system
并且这些PCI-E Riser都是通过线缆连接到主板上的
and these pcie risers are fully cabled and that basically makes
使得它们的维护非常简单，不需要工具进行拆解
them really easy to go service you don't need tools or anything like that to get in there so it makes them very easy to
这意味着你睾贵的GPU不需要花太多的时间在维护上
go work with and means that if you do have to go service the system your expensive gpus are not sitting idle for that long because you can more quickly
你可以更快地维护或者在机器后部添加设备
go and add things and service things in the back of the system that's definitely
如果你的机器价值千金，那你肯定也想要一款维护简单方便的服务器
what you want in a high value system like this
还有一些你在网上看不到的细节
something else that you might not see just if you're looking at the system online or something like that but what you can see if you're here is that
如果你把PCI-E Riser整个拔出来
if you pull out this pci riser assembly
你就能看到Riser下面还有两个m.2插槽
what you can actually see is that there are two m.2 slots that are below it kind of at the bottom of the system and why
它和普通的消费者主板上插槽有一点点区别
this actually kind of interesting is that they're a little bit different from some of the ones that you may have seen on like a consumer motherboard or
这些接口设置在主板的边缘
something like that these actually sit at the edge of the motherboard itself
把m.2硬盘插入后，通过另一端的免工具固定器就能安装好
and then you basically plug in the m.2 board and then you secure it using a tool-less assembly on the other end but
硬盘下面没有主板
there's no motherboard underneath it's actually just the drive and so it's a
这个设计让超微能够再加两个m.2接口给启动盘
way that super micro was able to actually add two m.2 slots for like boot media or something like that without
而不用拓展主板
having to actually extend the motherboard
好的，回到机箱的后方
okay and then moving to the back of the system what you're going to
能看到一些比较常规的部分，但和普通的超微服务器比又在排布上有些不同，总之是些比较常规的功能
see is that we have a pretty standard block it's a little bit different orientation from some of the other super micro systems that we've looked at but it's still pretty standard features we
有传统的VGA接口，两个USB 3接口
get a vga connector so legacy vga connector we also get two usb 3
这些接口能让你亲自给系统做维护
connectors and those allow you to service the system in person and you can actually just go and you know plug in a
比如插个KVM卡(keyboard video mouse)
kvm card you know keyboard video mouse
还能插个u盘啥的
card or you might have to go and plug in a usb drive or something like that you
这些接口在你必须肉身去维护的时候可堪一用
can totally do that using the ports that aren't backing system if you actually have to go out and physically service it
如果你不想这样，因为人工很贵嘛
now if you don't want to go out and physically service it because that's always pretty expensive what you can do
你还可以利用远程管理功能
is you can use remote management this
这台服务器拥有专用的外带管理口
has a dedicated out-of-band management
这个接口直接连接到BMC
port that's connected to the bmc so you
所以你不用到现场也能做维护
can basically do all of those functions without having to physically touch the server of course that always saves in
节约了服务器的维护费用，这点非常有用，并且在大多数服务器里都有这个功能
your service costs so it's something that's great it's in the system but it's also pretty standard on most servers
这台机器有两个网口
these days something that is pretty interesting though is that we get two additional network ports now these are
看起来像普通的RJ45接口，但实际上是10G BaseT接口
just look like standard rj45 parts but they're actually 10g based t ports so we
也就是万兆电口
do get 10 gig networking on here now in
用上像这样的服务器，你大概也不会用10G接口或者10G电口做互联
a system like this you're probably not going to rely on 10 gigabit or 10g base
你肯定会加IB网卡或者100G以太网卡
t networking you're most likely going to put things like either infiniband cards or maybe 100 gig ethernet cards or
甚至是DPU
something like that maybe even dpus in
但我觉得有了总比没有好吧
the system but at the same time i think that this is something that you know it is kind of nice that you do get that 10g
都那么贵的机器了，有个10G网口算是个小小的优势吧（注：这些口是给水冷用的，但这台机器是风冷的）
base t just in a system of this value and stuff like that is kind of nice to get that little bump
这台机器还可以插NVidia Bluefield2 DPU或者类似产品，以此提供更加现代的管理方法
this is also a system that is pretty interesting because you could use something like a nvidia bluefield dpu in here and actually get some of the kind of more modern ways to go and manage the system
这不是服务器内置的东西，但是可以利用后面的扩展槽进行添加
so that's not necessarily built into the system but it is something that you could add using these expansion slots in
好的，接着我们来介绍一位重量级
the rear okay and now let's talk about
也就是这个电源
the big things which are the power supplies
这个电源是一颗3000w 80PLUS 钛金电源
these things are three kilowatt 80 plus titanium units which means that
转换效率很高，给这台电老虎用属于是门当户对了
they're high efficiency which you definitely want in a system that can use as much power as this system but they're
要注意的一点是，因为它的功率非常高
also just just giant honking power supplies one quick note because they do use so much power it also means that
所以这块电源只适用于200V+的电压，或者说200V到240V电压
these are basically 200 plus or say 200 to 240 volt power supply so if you do
如果你的机柜是120V的，那就不要选这台服务器了
have a kind of more like 120 volt rack or something like that this is not the kind of system that you would use in
更加低端的服务器更加适合你，因为这台服务器消耗的电力太多了
that you probably want to have a lower end system just because this does use a lot of power
嘿大伙们，希望你们喜欢这期对超微NVidia红石平台的展示视频
hey guys i hope you enjoyed this look at this super micro nvidia redstone platform
我们看过了四块SXM4  A100 GPU组成的HGX平台
the fact that we get the HGX A100 with its four sxm4 gpus
这些都是高功耗，高性能的GPU
that are you know high powered gpus high performance gpus we also get the third
以及代号IceLake的第三代至强可扩展处理器和相关的新一代技术
generation intel xeon scalable processors codenamed icelake and all the technology that comes around with that new generation
我认为相较于上一代，这款服务器有了巨大的进步
i think this system is absolutely awesome and it is a definitely big step up from the previous generation
谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢
关注原作者！！